SamuelBrandão

Software Engineer

contact

Via Ruggero Leoncavallo, 10 Milan, 20131 - Italy

+39 3894570300

gb.samuel@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sambrandao

languages

portuguese native english fluency italian fluency

programming

♥ Python 3 ♥ Ruby (& Rails) PostgreSQL, MySQL MongoDB Git

> C JavaScript Angular, JQuery CSS3 & HTML5

> > F#

PHP & Wordpress Erlang Scala (Basic) Java

concepts

♥ Functional Programming
♥ Software Design
♥ Agile development
♥ BDD Workflows
Database Design
MetaProgramming
Maintainability

summary

Accomplished software engineer with 5+ years of experience building products (SaaS) using a range of technologies including Ruby/Rails, Python and JavaScript with multiple frameworks, relational and NoSQL databases.

experience

apr/2015-Now Senior Developer at 77Agency

Developer

As the main Ruby on Rails developer reponsible for Allin1social (a social media analytics / benchmarking application), I've successfuly improved the data retrieval, integration and processing mechanism, both by optimizing existing tasks and also by applying advanced heuristics which led to an 82% reduction of the overall daily/hourly workload. Dealt with critical MongoDB collections redesign, code quality analysis and control, implementation of automated tests and of BDD as a development workflow. I also performed a leadership role for a small team of developers working on the product.

2004-apr/2015 Freelance Developer

Brazil, Italy, Brazil

Università degli Studi di Milano

Italy

Developer

Worked as a Freelance Developer since approximately 2005, having worked with a coprehensive set of technologies, including Ruby, Python, PHP (using Codelgniter, Wordpress, Magento), JS/CoffeeScript, AngularJs and ReactJs.

particular projects

2012-2014 **Miviro**

http://www.miviro.com.br

Lead Developer

Miviro is a social network/management tool for tour agencies, developed with Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS3 and plenty of Javascript/Ajax. I've implemented dozens of functionalities, redesigned the overall app and database. Implemented a natural query interface to the database.

2011 Wertix CMS

ertix CMS Standalone project

Lead Developer

Wertix was a Content Management System developed from scratch as a mean to practice and learn the Ruby on Rails framework.

education

2011–2015 Bachelor of Computer Science, graduated *cum laude*

Laurea in Informatica

about me

I started programming at the age of 11 and working professionaly at the age of 19. While being a self-taught programmer contributed significantly to my problem solving skills, I decided to pursue a more conscious and comprehensive knowledge of the computing ecosystem, enrolling for a Bachelor Degree in Milan/Italy, which I completed *cum laude* in april 2015. I've also worked as a professional (theater) actor in Brazil, for more than 5 years! As a result, I love speaking in public, presenting ideas, products or projects. My ideal work scenario is a team-based product-centered development environment.